Animation Number 1
Wait, whoa!
（月火(つきひ)）って… うわ！
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Nadeko-chan!
（月火）撫子(なでこ)ちゃん！
（千石(せんごく)）あっ
You surprised me! Wh-Why are you in Onii-chan's bed?
（月火）びっくりした！
ど… どうして撫子ちゃんが
お兄ちゃんのベッドにいるの？
I totally thought I was embracing him!
私は お兄ちゃんを
抱き締めていたはずなのに
Morning, Tsukihi-chan.
（千石）おはよう 月火ちゃん
Y-Yeah. Morning, Nadeko-chan.
（月火）
う… うん
おはよう 撫子ちゃん
I get it. My brain's finally working.
ああ 分かったよ
やっと頭が働いてきた
Onii-chan found you and brought you over, didn't he?
お兄ちゃんが撫子ちゃんを見つけて
家に連れてきたんだね
In other words, he let you have the bed and is sleeping downstairs.
つまり お兄ちゃんは
撫子ちゃんにベッドを譲って
１階で寝てるんだ
What a gentleman!
紳士だね〜
Y-Yeah...
うん？　どうしたの 撫子ちゃん
What is it, Nadeko-chan? Feeling off?
気分でも悪いの？
そんなふうにうつむいて
If you're looking down like that, I can't see your cute face.
せっかくのかわいい顔が
見えないよ
Animation Number 23
C
u
Animation Number 23
t
e
Animation Number 23
D-Don't say cute face and stuff...
（千石）
か… かわいい顔とか言わないでよ
I'm not cute.
かわいくなんか ないもん
I just hang
Animation Number 23
my head
even lower.
Animation Number 23
I-I'm not cute at all.
（千石）
な… 撫子は
かわいくなんかない
What are you saying? You're cute!
え〜 何 言ってんの？
かわいいじゃない
You're cute, Nadeko-chan. Very cute. Super cute!
撫子ちゃん かわいいじゃん
すごくかわいいじゃん
超かわいいじゃん
I
Animation Number 26
The cutest organism on Earth isn't a stretch.
地球上で最もかわいい生き物だと
言っても過言じゃないじゃん
It's written "must be loved" it's so cute.
“愛す可(べ)し”と書いて
“可愛(かわい)い”じゃん
meant to say something,
Animation Number 30
Cutely, cutely cute! You're cute!
かわいくて かわいくて
かわいくて かわいいじゃん！
but her repeated saying
Animation Number 32
小学２年生の４月
When we started the 2nd year together back in April, the first thing that came to mind was, "Wow, how cute!"
同じクラスになったとき
すぐ思ったもん
うわ かわいいって
of "cute" silenced me.
Animation Number 35
"She's the cutest right after me!"
私の次にかわいいって
Animation Number 36
The moment I saw you I thought, "Oh, I have to be friends with her!"
見た瞬間 思ったもん
あっ
この子と友達にならなくちゃって
Animation Number 37
Th-Then i-if I weren't cute,
（千石）じゃ… じゃあ
も… もしも
撫子が かわいくなかったら
you wouldn't have become friends with me back then, Tsukihi-chan?
月火ちゃんは あのとき
撫子と友達には
なってくれなかったのかな
（月火）
ん？　何それ どういう意味？
What's that? What do you mean?
I-I'm sorry. I-It's nothing!
（千石）ご… ごめんなさい
な… 何でもないの
"Sorry" isn't what I want to hear. I asked what you meant.
ごめんなさいとかじゃないよ
私は“どういう意味？”って
聞いたんだよ
Can you answer me, Nadeko-chan?
答えてくれるかな 撫子ちゃん
Animation Number 42
Or are you unable to? Or you don't want to?
それとも
私からの質問には答えられない
答えたくない
ということなのかな？
I-I'm sorry.
（千石）ご… ごめんなさい
I said I didn't want you to say you're sorry. What, I'm not asking it right? Is it my fault?
（月火）
だから
ごめんなさいとかじゃなくてさ
なに？　私の聞き方が悪いの？
私のせいなの？
Or are you apologizing because you feel guilty about something?
それとも
何か後ろめたいことがあるから
謝ってるのかな？
I'm scared I'm scared I'm scared.
Animation Number 47
I-It's not...
（千石）ち… 違う
Animation Number 48
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What answer will make her hit me?
Animation Number 50
Okay, time to hit you...
（月火）
よし 殴ろう
She'll hit me even if I say nothing
Animation Number 51
腹を！
In the gut!
Hold on!
ちょっと待って！
言う 言う 言う！
I'll say it! I'll say it! I'll say it!
Critical point reached
Animation Number 54
Y-You see, I was told by this person, "Good thing you happen to be cute."
そ… そのね
言われたの そんなこと
ある人から
“たまたまかわいくて
よかったね”って
Technically, she's a vampire, not a person
Animation Number 55
Sort of
Animation Number 57
"Good thing you happen to be cute."
（月火）
〝たまたまかわいくて
よかったね？〞
I-It's not like I chose to be... Being shown favoritism just for that...
（千石）
撫子は
好きでかわいいわけじゃないもん
かわいいだけで
ひいきされるのが…
...makes you feel guilty? So that's why you grew out your bangs and hide your face like that?
後ろめたい
だから そうやって撫子ちゃんは
前髪を伸ばして顔を隠してるの？
And why you dress down on a daily basis and wear all those unstylish clothes...
（月火）
そして だから ふだんから
オシャレとかせずに
あんなダッサい服ばかり着てるんだ
...like that tasteless scrunchie.
（月火）
そんな趣味の悪いシュシュとか
つけてるんだ
So that's what it was...
（月火）そういうことだったのか
うん
じゃあ そういうところを含めて
Well, taking that into account, let me give you a word of advice.
ひとつだけね 私から
アドバイスをさせてもらうと
A-Advice?
（千石）ア… アドバイス？
Yeah, listen closely. Um...
（月火）うん よく聞いてね
えっと〜
I get what you're trying to say, but isn't it your fault that all you are is cute?
撫子ちゃんの言いたいことは
分かったけれど
それは でも
かわいいだけの撫子ちゃんが
悪いんじゃないの？
Tsukihi said:
Animation Number 79
Idiot!
バ〜カ！
Drastic measures.
Animation Number 82
Who told you that in the first place?
（月火）
大体 誰に言われたのよ そんなこと
Wh-Who?
だ… 誰って…
Animation Number 85
Onii-chan, by any chance?
お兄ちゃん？　ひょっとして
N-Never. He would never say anything like that...
（千石）そ… そんな
暦おにいちゃんは
そんなことは言わないよ
Animation Number 87
Speaking of which, you're in love with him, right?
っていうか撫子ちゃんって
お兄ちゃんのことが
好きなんだよね？
My big secret.
Animation Number 89
Wh-What are you talking about? Do you have proof?
な… 何のことかね
証拠でもあるのかね
I sounded like the criminal in an old mystery novel.
Animation Number 93
Well, you don't have to hide it.
It's obvious. It's apparent.
いや 別に隠さなくてもいいんだよ
見え見えだし バレバレだし
He's probably the only one who hasn't noticed.
気付いてないの
多分 お兄ちゃんくらいだし
So, Nadeko-chan, how'd you fall in love with him in the first place?
そもそも 撫子ちゃん
どうしてお兄ちゃんのことを
好きになったの？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
H-How?
（千石）ど… どうしてって…
The only time you had contact with him was when we were in 2nd grade, right?
（月火）
撫子ちゃんとお兄ちゃんに
接点があったのって
It goes back to when he was six years old
Animation Number 101
小学２年生の
あのころだけでしょ？
It goes back to when he was six years old
Animation Number 101
Then how were you able to keep being in love with him for all this time?
なのに どうして
お兄ちゃんのことを
The next six years
Animation Number 103
好きでい続けることが
できたの？
The next six years
Animation Number 103
It goes back to when he was six years old
Animation Number 101
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What could that be called? It seems to me it's far more than being "madly in love."
それって なんだろう
私から見れば
一途という域を
軽快に超えちゃっているような気が
するんだけど
W-Well...
そ… その…
（月火）
一応
するまでもない確認するけれど
I'll double-check. Not that I need to.
This "being in love" with him you're speaking of
撫子ちゃんの言う
お兄ちゃんが好きっていうのは
あれなんだよね？
isn't about him as a "kind brother" or "just a friend." It's not, right?
優しいおにいさんとしてとか
友達としてとか
Animation Number 112
Animation Number 114
そういうことじゃないんだよね？
It's like you want to go steady with him or be lovers. That kind of love, right?
お兄ちゃんと つきあいたいとか
恋人同士になりたいとか
Animation Number 116
Animation Number 118
そういう意味での
“好き”なんだよね？
Love as a member of the opposite sex
Animation Number 120
Y-Yeah, that's right.
う… うん　そうだよ
You want to make out with him, right?
（月火）
イチャイチャしたいんだよね？
I-I do, yeah.
し… したい　そう
And do this and that...
（月火）
あんなことや こんなことを
I do...
したい
The serpent on my right wrist——
Animation Number 125
said nothing, did nothing.
I acted like it wasn't there.
Animation Number 125
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I-I'm in love with Koyomi-oniichan.
な… 撫子は
暦おにいちゃんのことが好き
I love him as a man.
男の人として… 好き
Animation Number 127
I see.
そう
But he has a girlfriend, you know.
でも お兄ちゃん 彼女いるよ
Nadeko Medusa         Part Three
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Animation Number 130
んっ ハア ハア…
Time stood still
Animation Number 130
（月火）
ふ〜ん
Time stood still
Animation Number 130
I see. So you knew after all.
そっか　やっぱり知ってたんだ
Now, Nadeko-chan...
さて 撫子ちゃん
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Since we're both women, let's have a heart-to-heart.
（ドアが閉まる音）
（月火）女同士—
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
腹を割って話そうか
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
When did you find out?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
いつ知ったの？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Wh-When was it...
（千石）い… いつっていうか
I often spot him walking alongside other women...
暦おにいちゃんが
女の人と歩いているの—
よく見かけるし
Stop being spotted so often, Bro.
よく見かけられてるん
じゃねえよ！　兄(あに)！
And it's a different woman each time, so I thought that none of them were his girlfriend.
（千石）
そのたびに違う女の人だから
まあ でも
彼女とかではないんだろうなとは
思っていたけれど
My brother's too careless.
私の兄がうかつすぎる
But one among them was obviously his girlfriend, a perfect match for him.
でも そんな中に 一人だけ
見るからに恋人っていう
お似合いの人が
Just different.
Animation Number 144
A perfect match, you say...
Just different.
Animation Number 144
（月火）
お似合いの人ね
Just different.
Animation Number 144
Someone who stood out
was with him.
Animation Number 144
True, she's a perfect match. To the point that she's the only one for him.
確かにお似合いだな あの人は
お兄ちゃんには
あの人しかいないってくらいに
He didn't treat her like his younger sister
Animation Number 145
Everyone thinks he's the only one for her,
みんな あの人には
お兄ちゃんしかいないと
思ってるかもしれないけれど
and, of course, not like an older sister either——
Animation Number 145
but it's really the opposite.
本当は逆なんだよね
I think that was around last month...
（千石）
それが先月くらいのことだったかな
あ… いや もう11月だから
先々月か
Oh, no, it's already November, so the month before last.
（月火）ふ〜ん
What's problematic for me now is, "How does Nadeko-chan, knowing Onii-chan has a girlfriend,
私が今 問題にしているのは
どうして撫子ちゃんは
お兄ちゃんに彼女がいることを
知っているのに
continue to be in love with him?"
それでもなお お兄ちゃんのことを
好きでい続けるのか
ということだからね
P-Problematic...
（千石）も… 問題にされてるんだ
What, you're saying it's not?
（月火）
何よ　問題じゃないって言うの？
B-Because I don't really...
だ… だって別に撫子は
I don't really plan on stealing him away, and it's not even like I could.
別に撫子は略奪愛を
もくろんでいるわけじゃないし
横取りなんてできないし
If he says he has a girlfriend, I have no intent of troubling him...
彼女がいるっていうなら
それなら
迷惑をかけるつもりはないし
Just being in love is enough for me...
Animation Number 159
That's what I'm saying is the problem!
それが問題だって
言ってんでしょうが！
It's so obvious you love him, yet you don't want to go steady or be lovers with him.
見え見えなくらい好きなくせに
つきあいたいわけじゃないとか
恋人になりたいわけでもないとか
I have no idea what you're talking about.
それって何を言ってるのか
全然 分かんないじゃない
In other words, to you, he's like just some TV star,
つまり お兄ちゃんって
撫子ちゃんにとっては
ブラウン管の中のアイドルとか
I love him as a member of the opposite sex,
Animation Number 168
or a hero from manga.
漫画の中のヒーローとかと同じで
so can I really stop at that?
Animation Number 170
Someone you long for but never get? Is that it?
ただの憧れの存在に
すぎないってこと？
"Stop at that"...
Animation Number 174
That doesn't mean
that my feelings are fledgling.
Animation Number 174
I'm saying that sounds uncertain.
（月火）
なんだか あやふやだって
言ってるんだよ 私は
For someone that's been in love since the 2nd grade, you're being awfully acquiescent.
小学２年生のころから
ずっと好きだったってわりに
変に物分かりのいいことを
言っているし
But if I start thinking that's the way things are, you'll invite him over, entice him with skimpy outfits,
そうかと思えば
家に誘ったり 薄着で挑発したり
lie out on the bed, act assertively, and pretend you don't know he has a girlfriend.
ベッドで寝たり 積極的だったり
彼女がいることを
見て見ぬふりをしていたり
And yet, you're not giving up on him, and you seem happy when you make him worry about you.
だからといって諦めるわけでもなく
お兄ちゃんに心配をかけて
うれしそうにしているし
I-It doesn't make me happy...
（千石）
う… うれしそうになんて…
If I can be blunt about the impression I'm getting...
（月火）
私が受けている感想を
率直に言わせてもらえるなら
そうだね
Let's see...
She's telling me I
Animation Number 186
It feels like a romance you know will never come to fruition, and thus reassured, you keep it up.
love someone
Animation Number 186
絶対にかなわない恋愛を
and to never change that
Animation Number 186
She's telling me I love someone out of reach
or entirely fictitious
Animation Number 186
just so that I won't be hurt
Loving someone who won't turn you down
Animation Number 186
sure is
the easy way out
Animation Number 186
安心してやっているって
感じなのかな
Thanks to you being in love with him, life's been pretty easy for you up until now, right?
お兄ちゃんを好きだったおかげで
撫子ちゃんは これまで
随分と楽だったんじゃないの？
（千石）ど… どういう意味？
Wh-What do you mean?
I mean, it was easy for you to decline when some other boy asked you out, right?
（月火）
だから
誰か男の子から
告白されたときとかに
断りやすかったでしょ？
ほかに好きな人がいるからって
Because you could say, "I'm in love with someone else."
Actually I
Animation Number 192
turned down a confession from a boy on the baseball team
in my first term with that exact reason.
Animation Number 192
Tsukihi-chan, I merely want to avoid troubling Koyomi-oniichan.
（千石）月火ちゃん
撫子は単純に
暦おにいちゃんに
迷惑をかけたくないだけなんだよ
Trouble?
（月火）迷惑を？
Y-Yeah... I-I think I said it earlier too, but trouble is something I don't want...
さ… さっきも言ったと思うけど
迷惑だけは
O-Or is that a bad thing? Am I not allowed to continue just being in love with him?
そ… それともダメなの？
好きでいるだけのことが
許されないって言うの？
もちろん
迷惑のかけようがないことも
Of course, I know that there's no way to cause any trouble to him, either.
分かってるんだけどね
There's no way I'd win against her.
あの人に
撫子が勝てるとも思わないもの
If I were a boy... no, even as a girl...
男の子だったら
ううん 女の子でも
when I hear those assertions of yours, Nadeko-chan, I of course think "How cute."
そういう撫子ちゃんの主張を
やっぱり
かわいいって思うんだろうな
"Petty, but admirable and cute."
いじましくって
けなげで かわいいって
You know how people buy lottery tickets? Even though such a thing is very rarely a winner?
宝くじ買う人っているじゃない？
あんなの 普通に買ってて
当たるわけがないのにさ
Yet, if you ask them why they buy the tickets despite that, they say "I'm buying my dreams."
それなのに
なんで買うのかといえば
夢を買ってるっていうんだけど
That's
Animation Number 210
a major
thing
Animation Number 210
Every time I hear that, I can't help but think...
その言葉を聞くたびに
私なんかは思っちゃうわけだよ
"Buy reality."
現実を買え
Animation Number 212
I think when people say, "follow your dreams," it really means "look at reality."
Reference
夢を見ろっていう言葉は
現実を見ろって意味だと
思うんだけどね 私は
The stationary glittering in her right hand is...
Animation Number 212
If you were actually going to confess to Onii-chan...
もしも 撫子ちゃんが
本当にお兄ちゃんに
告白するつもりだったり
If you were planning on fighting her, I was thinking about cheering for you.
あの人と戦うつもりだったりしたら
応援したいなって思ってたし
At the least, I would've stayed quiet and observed the battle. I always thought that until now...
少なくとも黙って見守っていようと
思ったけれど
今まで
ずっとそう思っていたけれど
But I've had enough. I'm bored of this.
もういいや
もう飽きた
I'll end it all for you.
私が終わりにしてあげる
Drastic Measures
Animation Number 222
Animation Number 224
Old Friend
Sitting here in stupor solves nothing.
Animation Number 225
Well then, I will
Animation Number 227
scream.
Animation Number 229
I ask for your attention.
Animation Number 231
One, two,
Animation Number 233
A
h
いやあああああ！
A
h
Animation Number 236
Animation Number 240
I don't remember what happened afterward.
（千石）
それからのことは
よく覚えていません
It's vague. It's uncertain.
曖昧です　あやふやです
Impossible...
Beware
of
Rail
Crossing
（千石）ありえない
Impossible, impossible, impossible...
ありえない ありえない
ありえない ありえない…
Karen fixed
Animation Number 244
my hairstyle
somewhat,
Animation Number 244
but there was no hiding
the difference in style between my bangs, sides, and nape.
Animation Number 244
No, no. Having escaped from reality, that's inevitable, Nadeko-chan. Huh?
（クチナワ）
いやいや 現実逃避をしていても
しかたねえだろ 撫子ちゃん
ああん？
Relax. You're cute enough.
大丈夫だって
ちゃんとかわいいから
Cu...
Cu?
I am not cute!
かわいくなんてない！
Nanahyakuichi Middle School / Entrance
Animation Number 264
A girl I've never seen before.
Animation Number 266
Like I said, not cute.
やっぱりかわいくないよ この子
A new style.
Animation Number 267
It's just if...
（クチナワ）もしも
Suddenly the serpent had
Scene 268
It's just if you really think about your bangs that much...
（クチナワ）もしも 本当に
そこまで
前髪のことが気になるんならよ
I'm not against fixing them for you. What do you say, huh?
それ
俺様が直してやってもいいんだぜ
ああん？
a proposal.
Animation Number 269
Y-You can do such a thing?
そ… そんなこと… できるの？
I'm a god. If you can get my vessel back for me,
（クチナワ）俺様は神様だぜ
撫子ちゃんが もしも
俺様の神体を取り戻してくれたら
前髪を伸ばすくらいの願い
かなえてやらないでもない
it's not like I wouldn't grant a simple wish like growing out bangs.
I see...
なんだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
No, no, Nadeko-chan. You might be able to find it as early as tonight.
（クチナワ）いやいや 撫子ちゃん
早ければ今晩にでも
見つけることが
できるかもしれねえぜ
My vessel, that is.
俺様の神体をよ
What do you mean?
（千石）どういうこと？
Thanks to Koyomi-oniichan trying to set you on the right path,
（クチナワ）
暦おにいちゃんが撫子ちゃんを
補導してくれたおかげで
I got a clue as to where my vessel is.
俺様の神体がどこにあるのか
当てがついたってことだぜ
Kuchinawa-san, that clue is...
（千石）
クチナワさん
その当てっていうのは？
Oh, I'm going to shut up.
（クチナワ）あっ 俺様 黙るわ
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Sengoku...
（教師･･笹薮(ささやぶ)）
千石
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Sasayabu-sensei
Animation Number 283
Hmm?
I-I seem to have mistaken you for someone else. Sorry.
ひ… 人違いだったな　すまん
He begins to leave in confusion
Animation Number 285
Oh, it's me, Sengoku.
（千石）あっ いえ 千石です
I'm Sengoku Nadeko.
千石撫子です
Sengoku, is that what you really look like?
（笹薮）
千石…
それが お前の真の姿だったのか？
He coughs
Animation Number 288
It's obviously fake
Sengoku, what happened with that case I asked you about earlier? Any new developments?
千石 この間 頼んでいた件は
どうなった？
あれから何か進展はあったか？
How's it going to get solved in one day?
Animation Number 292
Like I usually did, I lowered my eyes, looked down, and stayed quiet.
（千石）
撫子は いつもどおり
目を伏せてうつむいて
黙り込むだけです
Having done so, let's wait for Sasayabu-sensei to become unsettled and walk away.
そうやって
笹薮先生があきれて立ち去るのを
待ちましょう
And length of time aside,
Animation Number 292
it's likely never going to get solved.
Going on standby.
Animation Number 292
Why is it?
（千石）
どうしてなのでしょう
Has something changed between yesterday and today?
昨日と今日で
何か状況が変わったのでしょうか？
Of course! It has to be my hairstyle.
そんなもの
撫子のヘアスタイルに決まってます
Even with my eyes closed and looking down...
目を伏せていようと
うつむいていようと
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Sasayabu-sensei has a clear view of my face...
撫子の顔は
笹薮先生から丸見えなのです
If he can see my facial expressions, it's obvious to him that I'm not troubled so much.
表情が見えてしまっていれば
撫子が言うほど困ってないことが
バレてしまうのでした
I have no choice.
しかたありません
それらしい言い訳をして
この場を切り抜けるとしましょう
Let's make up some likely excuse and get through this scene.
For starters, like I usually do...
まずは いつもどおり
Let's go with that.
Animation Number 301
Bangs or no bangs, like I always do,
前髪があろうとなかろうと
いつもどおりに いつものように
start off with "I'm sorry," and take it from there...
ごめんなさいから切り出して
あとはその場の流れで
I wonder if a normal excuse will do it.
Animation Number 302
Shut the hell up!
（千石）うっせえんだよ！
Wait. Did someone just say something?
（千石）
あれ？　誰か何か言いましたか？
Of course there aren't any new developments! Don't go forcing all your work on me, huh?
進展なんか あるわけねえだろ！
俺様に てめえの仕事を
押しつけてんじゃねえぞ！
ああん？
Animation Number 314
Every time you look at my face, it's "What happened to that case? What happened to that case?"
人のツラ見りゃ
例の件は どうなった
例の件は どうなったって
どうなるもこうなるも ねえよ！
Like anything would ever happen! No way!
You know more than anyone else that you're asking for the impossible! Don't ya, huh?
むちゃな頼みごとだってことは
てめえが
いちばん分かってんだろうが
ああん？
Wh-What's the matter, Sengoku?
（笹薮）ど… どうしたんだ 千石
気安く触ってんじゃねえ
Don't get all chummy and touch me!
What do you think people are, dolls or something?
人を何だと思ってんだ
人形か何かか？
Hah!
I know I'm just a cute girl. No matter what people say, I just do as I'm told!
どうせ俺様は かわいいだけだよ
何を言われたって
言われるがままだよ！
But that doesn't mean I don't have any emotions!
だけど だからって
何も感じてねえわけじゃねえぞ！
Don't assume the quiet ones are really quiet!
おとなしいヤツが
本当におとなしいと思ってんな！
H-Hey, Sengoku-san, what's wrong?
（男子生徒）
お… おい どうしたんだ 千石さん
Calm down. Come on, just calm down.
落ち着けよ　まあ 落ち着けって
You're probably just tired.
お前 なんか疲れてるんだって
Calm down? This is from being calm for so long...
落ち着け？
落ち着いていた結果がこれだろうが
And I'm tired? Can't you tell just by looking?
疲れてる？
見りゃ分かんだろうが
Se-Sengoku, I just believed in your sense of duty...
（笹薮）せ… 千石
ただ先生は
お前の責任感を信じて…
Like I have any sense of duty!
責任感なんて俺様にあるか！
千石撫子が
どれぐらいダメなヤツかくらい
You shoulda seen that Sengoku Nadeko is a good-for-nothing!
ちゃんと見抜け！
Don't be fooled by looks! Get a grip!
見た目にだまされてんじゃねえぞ
しっかりしろ
そうだよ 俺様は
ただ かわいいだけなんだよ！
That's right, I got nothing going for me except being cute!
Don't go believing someone like this!
こんなヤツ 信じてんじゃねえ！
This is contrary to everything I ever did.
Animation Number 340
Wh-Where are you going, Sengoku?
（笹薮）
ど… どこへ行くんだ？　千石
Huh?
ああん？
Isn't it obvious? I gotta do it, so I'm gonna go do my job as Class Prez for ya!
決まってんだろうが
しかたねえから
委員長としての仕事ってやつを
してやるんだよ！
You're the one that forced it on me! Rejoice, you idiot!
てめえの言いつけだろうがよ
喜べ ボケ！
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
フン！
Hey, riffraffs!
おい 有象無象
How about a reply, riffraffs?
返事はどうした！　有象無象！
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
All right, guys, look at reality!
いいかお前ら 現実を見ろよ
I yelled.
Animation Number 369
All of you are moping about things past, and wasting precious time as adolescents.
過ぎたことで
いつまでもウジウジとして
貴重な青春時代を
台なしにしやがって
I talked on——
Animation Number 370
Do you guys realize how pointless all that is?
どんだけムダなことをしてるか
分かってんのか？
Countless times
Animation Number 371
If who you thought was a friend was jealous of ya, that's enough to end the friendship?
お前らは
友達だと思ってたヤツが
自分のことを妬んでたら
それで
もう友達じゃなくなるのか？
ウソをつかれたら
それで終わりか？
Is it all over if someone lies to ya?
You've gotta come to terms at some point, or stuff like this goes on forever!
適当なところで
折り合いをつけねえと
いつまでも
こんな状況が続くんだぞ
Maybe you're just
Animation Number 372
lying low,
trying to change classes in April,
Animation Number 372
but you're gonna be
carrying the memory forever!
Animation Number 372
Then it's no good unless you paint over those memories! Overwrite them!
だったら
塗り替えなきゃダメだろうが
書き換えなきゃダメだろうが
Change them into memories of
"I couldn't trust anyone because
“一時期は変なおまじないのせいで
誰も信用できなかったけど”
of these weird charms, but we all made up in the end"!
“ちゃんと仲直りしました”って
思い出によ！
Yeah, you guys are the worst bunch ever!
ああ 確かにお前たちは最低だ
Hypocrites that talk principles and hide your real intentions!
本音と建て前を使い分ける偽善者だ
Scum of the earth that betray once someone believes you! The lowest forms of life on Earth!
信じた先から裏切る
この世のクズだ！
地球上で最も下等な生き物だ
But... But there musta been some truth somewhere in there!
だけど！
だけど
どっかに本当もあったはずだろうが
I yelled from the bottom of my heart.
Animation Number 378
Maybe there was a bit of truth inside that lie!
ウソだって
本当だったかもしれねえだろ！
Lies! Betrayal! Deception! Hypocrisy!
ウソや 裏切りや 欺瞞(ぎまん)や 偽善を
Why don't any of you have a heart big enough to forgive all that! Huh?
許してやれる度量を持ちやがれや
ああん？
Since when are you so great that you can cherry-pick the people around you?
いつから お前たちは
人をえり好みできるほど
偉くなったんだ？
好き嫌いで
人づきあいしてんじゃねえよ！
Don't hang out with people based on whether you like them or not!
I said one last thing. I yelled it.
Animation Number 384
I hate all of you! But god damn it, you're all my classmates!
俺様は お前たちなんか大嫌いだ！
だけど クラスメートだぜ
こんちきしょうが！
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 387
I left school early. I did, indeed.
（千石）
早退しました　しましたとも
Timed Traffic Light
I'm just walking around absentmindedly.
ぼんやり歩いています
I'm even more absentminded than when I went to school.
登校したときよりも ぼんやりです
No, now that I think about it, the walk to school was fun.
いや 今から思えば
楽しい通学路でしたよ 登校時は
Back then, what in the world was troubling my mind?
あのころ撫子は 一体
何を気に病んでいたのでしょう
I had no idea where I was going.
Animation Number 393
Really,
where
Animation Number 393
am I going?
You know, I'm going to bring up something that should be clear as water, Nadeko-chan.
（クチナワ）
つうか 言わずもがなのことを
確認させてもらうけどよ
撫子ちゃん
That tirade earlier... It wasn't that I took over your body and said whatever was on my mind.
別に さっきのは
撫子ちゃんの体を俺様が操って
好き放題 言って回ったって
わけじゃねえからな
Simply put, the effects of you assimilating me showed up pretty clearly...
単に俺様と同化した影響が
顕著に現れたというか
ふだん撫子ちゃんが
自分にかけている枷(かせ)が
It's just that the restraints you usually have on happened to disappear.
解けちまったってだけだ
I already know that. Shut up...
分かってるよ うるさいな
It was Nadeko. None other than Sengoku Nadeko...
あれは撫子
ほかの誰でもない千石撫子
撫子自身だよ
It was Nadeko herself. It was just Nadeko saying what she wanted to say.
撫子が
言いたいことを言ったってだけだよ
I know that. It's not that you're to blame, Kuchinawa-san.
分かってる
クチナワさんが悪いわけじゃない
Yeah, that's right. Since you understand...
（クチナワ）
ああ そのとおり
分かってんなら…
But I do think it is your fault, Kuchinawa-san.
でも
クチナワさんのせいだとは思う
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
For now, my life and my days at school have come to an "ending."
とりあえず
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
撫子の人生と学校生活は
終焉(しゅうえん)を迎えたとして
I try to change the topic.
Animation Number 403
So now, once and for all, let's end it, Kuchinawa-san.
だから もう
ついでに いっそ
全部終わらそうか クチナワさん
Huh?
（クチナワ）ああん？
You have a clue as to where your vessel is, right, Kuchinawa-san?
（千石）
クチナワさんの神体がある場所
もう当てがついてるんでしょ？
Let's hurry up and find it, Kuchinawa-san, and have you regain your original powers. And then...
早く
クチナワさんの神体を見つけて
それでクチナワさんは
本来の力を取り戻してもらって
それで…
...let's bid farewell.
お別れしよう
That will be the end of it all. Sound good?
それで全部終わり　いいよね？
I can't think about the rest.
Animation Number 410
Nothing comes to mind.
Sure. Sounds fine.
（クチナワ）ああ いいぜ
Then, tell me, Kuchinawa-san. Where should I go, and where should I look?
（千石）
じゃあ 教えてよ クチナワさん
撫子は どこに行って
どこを探せばいいの？
You should look in Koyomi-oniichan's house.
（クチナワ）
暦おにいちゃんの家だよ
The ending to everything is there.
全ての終わりが そこにある
Animation Number 415
Sealed up space means nothing against me!
密閉空間なんてもんは
この俺様には通用しねえっつ〜の
I am a being that nullifies all sorts of barriers!
あらゆる結界を無効化するのが
この俺様なんだぜ
But it's still mysterious...
（千石）でも やっぱり不思議だよ
Why is your vessel inside Koyomi-oniichan's house, Kuchinawa-san?
どうして クチナワさんの神体が
暦おにいちゃんの家の中にあるの？
My vessel was probably just carried away,
（クチナワ）
多分 どこかに持ち出されていた
俺様の神体を
found by someone, and entrusted to Koyomi-oniichan.
俺様よりも先に
探し出したヤツがいて
それを 暦おにいちゃんが
託されたってことだろうよ
Entrusted? By whom?
（千石）
でも 託されたって 誰から？
Who knows? Probably that specialist that wears Hawaiian shirts or something?
（クチナワ）さあな
アロハ服を着た
専門家じゃねえのかい？　どうせ
It's just a thought.
多分なんだけど
What Tsukihi-chan was saying is probably right.
月火ちゃんの言ってたこと
正しいんだよ
Huh?
（クチナワ）ああん？
The reason why I'm in love with Koyomi-oniichan. It's because if I am, I don't have to get hurt.
（千石）
撫子が
暦おにいちゃんを好きなのって
そうしていれば
傷つかずに済むからなんだよ
See, romance takes a whole lot of energy, right?
だってほら
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
恋愛って
すっごくエネルギーを使うじゃない
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
A Kuchinawa-san does not, however.
クチナワさんじゃないけど
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Falling in love with someone, someone falling for you...
人を好きになったり
なられたりして
Sometimes it's easier if you keep pining for a love that will never be yours.
だったら 絶対にかなわない恋に
身をやつしているのが
案外 楽だったりするもの
You don't have to look for someone else or choose.
目移りせずに済むし
迷わずに済むし
It's like Tsukihi-chan said.
月火ちゃんの言うとおり
Otherwise, you can't explain it, after all...
でなきゃ説明がつかないよね
やっぱり
Someone half-hearted like me continuing to be in love for six years
撫子みたいな いいかげんな子が
いちずに６年間も
with a friend's older brother whom I've barely gotten to know.
ちょっと知り合っただけの友達の
お兄ちゃんのことを
ずっと好きでい続けるだなんて
It's just unreasonable, right?
無理があるよね
If I were to force a reason...
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
（千石）
強いて言うなら
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"Sorry"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"It's awkward with someone older around,
but Tsukihi dragged me in."
Flashback
I'd say that it was because he was Araragi Koyomi.
彼が阿良々木暦
だったからと
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
Koyomi
Grade Schooler
"And then?"
Flashback
言うしかないでしょう
In other words, though it's not a phrase you'd normally use for a man
つまり あまり男の人に対して
使う言葉ではありませんけれど
I have to say I felt relieved being in love with someone as unattainable as the stars.
高嶺(たかね)の花だったから
安心して好きになったとしか
言えません
A dream that remains unfulfilled.
Animation Number 443
An ideal left unrealized.
An item never found.
Animation Number 443
Calling it that
let me live in peace.
Animation Number 443
うわ… わっ わあ〜！
Hey, Nadeko-chan?
（クチナワ）おい 撫子ちゃん？
A-Amazing! What a rabid fetish...
（千石）
す… すごい
こんなマニアックな…
さすが暦おにいちゃん
半端じゃない！
That's Koyomi-oniichan all right. Nothing half-hearted!
No, but this, all in all...
い… いや　でも これはこれで…
Hey, Nadeko-chan.
（クチナワ）おい 撫子ちゃん
Hush. Maybe your vessel is hidden between the pages of a book like this.
黙って！
ひょっとすると こういう本の
ページとページの隙間に
クチナワさんの神体が
あるかもしれないじゃない
Nadeko-chan!
（クチナワ）撫子ちゃん
Wh-What? Something about the girl on this page?
な… 何？
このページの女の子が何か？
No, not that... I meant that bookmark that was placed between those pages.
（クチナワ）いや じゃなくて
そのページに挟んであった
そのしおりのほうだよ
Bookmark?
（千石）しおり？
Wait, this isn't a bookmark, but a talisman?
これは しおりじゃなくて お札？
So that's how it is.
（クチナワ）そういうことか
So that's how it was preserved.
そういう形で保存してあったわけか
To think that my vessel wasn't preserved as a physical item, but as a drawing...
俺様の神体は物質としてじゃなく
画(え)として保存されていたと
I didn't expect that, heh...
想定外だぜ しゃしゃっ
The serpent had never been in this good a mood.
Animation Number 460
Here, Nadeko-chan. Hurry up and feed me that talisman.
ほれ 撫子ちゃん
さっさと そのお札を
俺様に食わせてくれよ
Feed?
食わせて…
Rest assured, I'll keep my promise. I'll make sure you have your bangs back.
（クチナワ）
安心しな　約束は守るぜ
撫子ちゃんの前髪は
ちゃんと復活させてやる
No, that won't be enough of a reward. If you have other wishes I'll grant them.
いや それだけじゃ
お礼としては足りないかな？
ほかにも願いがあれば
かなえてやるぜ
What? You don't have any wishes, Nadeko-chan? I don't care if they're overly ambitious.
（クチナワ）
ん？　ねえのかい？
撫子ちゃん 願い事
どんな高望みだってかまわないぜ
Overly ambitious...
高望み…
What should I wish for?
Animation Number 470
Unattainable as the stars...
What should I wish for?
Animation Number 470
（千石）
高嶺の花 願い事
What should I wish for?
Animation Number 470
Something for me, Sengoku Nadeko.
What is it that  I  want.
Animation Number 470
A wish.
What is it that  I  want.
Animation Number 470
What, you don't have it? Something that you'd want to wish upon a god?
（クチナワ）
ねえのかよ 撫子ちゃんには
神様に願いたいこと
Something I want to wish...
（千石）願いたいこと
Something you'd want to pray for, if you will.
（クチナワ）
祈りたいことでもいいんだけどよ
"My beloved..."
大好きな…
"My beloved Koyomi-oniichan, I want our feelings to become mutual."
大好きな暦おにいちゃんと
両想いになりたいとか
そんなお願いでも かなうのかな？
Would a wish like that come true, I wonder?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That one won't come true, Sengoku.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
そいつは かなわないな
千石
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）火憐だぜ
（月火）月火だよ
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Decoy
（火憐･月火）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ！
It's already been 2 years since we started helping people with our combined power.
How dare you trick
Nadeko-chan
like this!
Ha! Idiots!
（月火）
私たち ファイヤー
シスターズを結成し
人を助け続けて早２年
（火憐）
そう言うと短(みじけ)えな
Feels like yesterday.
Preview Quiz!
（月火）
予告編クイズ！
（火憐）
クイズ！
Quiz!
There's this saying: "The good you do for others is good you do yourself"; however...
（月火）
情けは人のためならずと
言いますが
（火憐）
ますが？
However?
I hear children often misinterpret it on purpose as:
（月火）
これを
〝情けをかけるのは〞
〝人のためにならない〞
"Never show compassion to others".
という意味の
ことわざだと
You will pay for
doing that to our friend!
間違って覚えちゃう
子供が
多いらしいんだよね
（火憐）
ああ 聞く聞く
Yeah, tell me about it.
What it really means though is that when you help people,
本当は
〝人助けっていうのは〞
you're not doing it for them, you're doing it for yourself.
〝相手のため
じゃなくて〞
〝自分のために
すること〞
って意味なんだよな
（月火）
でも そうなると
But in that case, doesn't it mean that helping people for your own sake is not necessarily wrong?
人のためにならない
っていう解釈も
You were a fool for trusting
him as well, Nadeko-chan.
Tsukihi-chan is scary when she snaps!
Punishment!
あながち間違いとは
言えないよね
You don't even take the other person into consideration because your only goal is to feel good about yourself.
自分を高めるために
情けをかけたんだから
相手の事情なんか
何も考えてないんだよ
（火憐）
それもまた
ひどい解釈だな
Right, another terrible way to look at it.
（月火）
考えちゃうよね
Makes you wonder when you help somebody, are you doing it for them or for yourself?
人助けをしよう
というとき
これは自分のために
やっているのか
While I was at it, I gave you a new look!
Eh!
Is that an act of virtue or hypocrisy?
相手のために
やっているのか
善なのか偽善なのか
Thinking about that would just stop you in your tracks.
（火憐）
そんなこと考えてたら
動けなくなっちゃうん
じゃねえの？
（月火）
つまり 情けは
So in the end, compassion exists to make people hesitate.
人をためらわす
というわけです
おあとが
よろしいようで
It's quite a good thing after all.
I'm not sure it can be considered good...
（火憐）
そんなに
よくなってねえぞ
Next time! Otorimonogatari Episode 4!
Next Time
Nadeko Medusa Part 4
（火憐･月火）
次回「囮(おとり)物語」第４話
Nadeko Medusa, Part 4.
「なでこメドゥーサ
其ノ肆(そのよん)」
Can I leave the rest in your hands?
Hey you!
Her personality changed
with her hairstyle!
（月火）
おあとは
よろしくなってるかな？
（火憐）
ひと事みてえに…
Don't make it sound like an order.